Hi everyone, welcome back.
Now we have seen the concept of ATM, ATM, ATM, Intrancy, Value and Extrancy.
I will show you the same website and I am going to take you to the NSC option chain.
NSC option chain is basically the website of the NSC India, where we are going to write different tracks.
As I saw in my example, we have also seen 100 tracks, 110 tracks, 80 tracks.
Same thing, we are going to write all the tracks on the same page and we are going to give you an option chain name.
So I will take you to the next one and we will talk about how we will know how to write it.
What is the ATM, what is the ATM, what is the ATM and we will do some calculations for Intrancy and Extrancy Value also.
So I am going to show you the option chain of this NSC.
As you can see, here it is nifty, so you can see that I have chosen nifty here.
You can choose stocks from index.
I have chosen the current expiry, weekly expiry 22 August.
And as I have said, as you can see the current price of nifty is going to be 24541.
And this is how the entire option chain looks like.
Now if you see, here there is a gray color on the right side and there is gray on the right side.
We always see on the left side, there are calls and there are putts on the right side.
The middle line, you will see the strike price as we have said, we can trade in different strikes and you will see the strike price of nifty.
So first I will discuss a little bit about what are the different columns.
The first column is the strike, it is clear that we can trade in different strikes.
On the left side, the OIS, which is called open interest, this is called calls open interest.
And then the change in open interest.
Change in open interest means that how many quantity change are there in color and today.
In color and today's situation, how many quantities change there?
We call it change in open interest.
What is open interest?
I will tell you in the next one, we will talk about it later.
But we just thought that we have a column open interest and change in open interest.
So, we have a column open interest and change in open interest.
Then we have the volume, this is a daily volume, how much is the volume of our purchase?
I.V. I.V. is the implied volatility.
We will discuss this later, when I will tell you about the other Greeks.
So, we will talk about I.V. then.
LTP is the last traded price, which means LTP is the life price.
The change means that what movement is there in the future?
Green color means positive movement and red is the negative movement.
And the last column of the right, the bid quantity, ask quantity, bid price and ask price.
Basically, the live bid and ask market is showing that.
So, the same thing you will see in the right side for the puts.
But the important point is that we are looking at strikes.
So, let me zoom in a little bit.
And let us see what the difference between strikes is.
So, because the current price is now at a price of 50,000 rupees.
That is approximately 254,541.
That means, the price is around Rs.4,550.
So, you will see that Rs.4,550 is the same.
You can see the difference between the green and white color.
Now, on the left side, we have seen that all the calls are seen.
Now, we have just talked about the strike price.
If the case of calls is increasing, then it becomes out of the money.
So, you will see that, as we are going down, Rs.4,640, Rs.2,650, Rs.2,720, Rs.2,750, Rs.2,420.
As we are going down, the strike is increasing.
We are going out of the money.
That is the white portion, which is the out of the money option.
In the case of calls, OTM is the option.
And the great option is the money option.
In the case of calls.
Because, you will see that the price here is already high.
That is, the level is going up.
Now, the option has already been added to some intrinsic value.
And if I see on the right side, there are some puts.
So, the white part of the OTM has already been added.
So, these are all the OTM.
And the gray ones are again two are the ITMs.
This is your ITM.
So, first of all, just by looking at the colors, we will see that,
The white color is the OTM and the gray color is the same.
And obviously, the Rs.4,550 is the raw one.
This is our addamanie.
Because, this is exactly the close to nifty.
The nifty is 24, 540.
So, this is the addamanie.
Now, let's look at our LTP.
So, if we talk about LTPs, which is this column,
This column is the LTP column.
So, you can see that, as we are going into the money,
The price of calls is increasing.
Which is also because, we already said that,
In the money, we already,
The nifty is going up.
So, if we don't move the market,
We will get some money.
So, the prices of the money, which are increasing in LTP,
They are going to get expensive.
And the amount of money, which is so far,
They will be cheap.
You can see, there is also a 20 rupees option.
Similarly, if I talk about the boot,
As we go to the OTM,
As my strike will be less,
In the case of boots,
My premium will be less.
And similarly, if they will come down,
They will be more premium.
So, this is our premium.
So, let us do some calculation.
Now, let me do some calculation for you.
Listen to me.
We are going to buy an Indamanie call option,
Because, we will get the market up.
So, the 4-5-100.
The call we are going to buy,
Which is 176 rupees.
So, if we don't move the market,
What will our profit and loss be?
If we buy it,
Why are we buying it?
It seems to me that,
Expiry will come,
And drop the nifty job,
And it will go up.
So, let's do the calculation.
First, we know that,
The nifty is going to run,
2, 5,
2, 4, 5, 4, 0.
2, 4, 5, 4, 0 is going to run.
So,
This 176 rupees,
How much intrinsic value,
How much extrinsic value,
So,
Because nifty is 40 points,
If we calculate it,
Because nifty,
Because nifty is 40 points already in the money,
Which is our intrinsic value,
It is already 40 points,
For this strike.
How we calculated it,
2, 4, 5, 4, 0, minus,
24, 500, which is our strike price,
That means,
40 points is my intrinsic value.
That means, if nifty is also moved,
So, we will get 40 points back.
And the remaining remaining,
136.35,
That is our intrinsic value.
So, how much is our extrinsic value,
136.45 or 136?
What does it mean?
If nifty is 20 points,
Why is it 20 points?
Because we have expiring,
For 22 points,
So, if nifty is 20 points,
If we do not move one point,
Then how much will it be?
136 points will be lost,
Which is the extrinsic value.
Because we already discussed,
The loss of extrinsic value is the loss of the loss.
So, this is the case of ITM.
Let us see one example.
In the case of OTM also.
So, if nifty is too much,
It will be moved up to 400 to 700.
So, I will buy the call of 400 to 700,
Which is 72 rupees.
Because 72 rupees is going to be going.
So, again we can calculate our positive profit and loss.
Now, why is the 470 now?
It is out of the money.
So, this is completely 72 rupees.
It is my extrinsic value.
This complete 72 rupees is my extrinsic value.
Means, if nifty expires until 400 to 700,
It is going to be down.
So, this is completely 72 rupees.
I will give it to me.
Because this is completely,
It is completely extrinsic value.
So, this is the intrinsic value extrinsic value.
I can calculate very easily with very little extrinsic value.
Using this excel or using this page,
You can get a harsh tricter intrinsic value extrinsic value.
Similarly, let's do one calculation for puts also.
I think the market will be down.
It will be down.
But I think I am looking at 400 to 600.
I think that 400 to 600 will be down.
That 400 will be down.
Till expires.
So, I am buying 400 to 600 putt.
So, I am going to give it to me.
Which is approximately 137 rupees.
So, this putt option is going to be down.
I am going to buy it.
I am buying it.
I am buying it because I think it is down.
Till expires until 20 to 600 will be down.
Now, it is down.
Now, this time, this nifty already has to be down.
It is down.
Means, it already has to be down.
Now, it is down.
Means, there are already 60 points in the money.
What is this?
We have calculated it for 20 to 600 minus,
That is 20 to 500 is the current price of a nifty.
So, 60 points in the money.
That means my intrinsic value is 60 points and my extrinsic value is different from the one that is 137-60
That means 77 points.
77 points is my extrinsic value.
If the market does not move and expires here, then my total loss will be 77 points, not 137 points.
Because I have already got the intrinsic value.
So, you can see the options of NSC that are big and this is the data.
This is the update in every 2-3 minutes.
So, like you will see the market life.
You will see the life prices in every 2-3 minutes.
And you can calculate your calculation.
What is your intrinsic value? What is extrinsic value?
We will see the color code.
We will see that the OTM is here.
This is the OTM.
The top item is there.
And we can do the trading on its basis.